Middleboro, Mass. First Church of Middleboro records, 1702-1925.
Congregational Library & Archives
Middleboro, Mass. First Church of Middleboro records, 1702-1925.
RG4970
Congregational Library & Archives
2.22 Cubic Feet
(2 boxes, 2 reels)
The First Congregational Church of Middleboro was first organized on December 26, 1694 and Samuel Fuller was ordained as the first minister. The First meeting house had been constructed previously in 1680 and the second was constructed in 1701. Ecclesiastical differences between competing factions resulted in the congregation splitting and the third meeting house being constructed in 1745. The congregation remerged in 1754. The fourth and present meeting house was built in 1828. The congregation continues to serve the Middleboro community today. The collection contains valuable membership records along with administrative records, financial records, manuscript sermons, and print materials.
Conant, Sylvanus, 1720-1777
First Congregational Church (Middleboro, Mass.)
Thatcher, Peter, Jr., 1688-1744
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information is available for the Ecclesiastical council records, 1832, which originally formed the "Middleboro, Mass. First Church ecclesiastical records, 1832, RG0126."
No acquisition information is available for the microfilm surrogates of the 1707-1821 church record book. These microfilm surrogates were likely created in 2009 by the NEDCC. The location of the original ledger is currently unknown. These microfilm surrogates formed the "Middleboro, Mass. First Congregational Church records, 1707-1821, RG4919."
The remaining materials within the collection were placed on permanent loan to the Congregational Library & Archives by the First Church of Middleboro in the summer of 2011; accession 2011-08.
Accruals
Additional accruals are expected for this collection in the form of full-text transcription. There is no anticipated date for this accrual.
Historical Note
The area of Middleborough was first settled by English colonizers from the Plymouth Colony in March 1662 after the purchase of land from the Native American sachem, Wampatuck. The settlement was destroyed in 1675 during the King Phillips War. It was resettled in 1679. Among the new group of settlers was Samuel Fuller, son of Dr. Samuel Fuller of the Mayflower, who acted as minister for the new settlement. The first meetinghouse was constructed in 1680. The First Congregational Church in Middleboro, also referred to as the First Church of Christ, was organized on December 26, 1694 (O.S.) and Fuller was ordained the same day. Fuller died the following summer.
The second meetinghouse was constructed in 1701 and the First was auctioned off shortly after. Rev. Peter Thacher oversaw a revival movement during his ministry which ended with his death in 1744. Following his death, ecclesiastical differences between the "standing party" and the "revival men" resulted in a split in the congregation. The "standing party" maintained the majority of the congregation and the second meetinghouse. This group called Rev. Thomas Weld to be their pastor. The "revival men" built a third meetinghouse in 1745 and called Sylvanus Conant as their pastor. In 1746, George Whitefield preached from the third meetinghouse and tradition holds that the building was so crowded that Whitefield could only leave by climbing out a window behind the pulpit. The church reunified in 1749 after the dismission of Weld.
The fourth, and current, meeting house was built in 1828 and designed by the architect, James Sproat. Sproat had joined the church in 1816 and he later became a deacon in 1833. The building was dedicated in 1829 and the dedication sermon was preached by Rev. Lyman Beecher. The church largely saw growth during the nineteenth-century.
After the General Council of Congregational Churches voted to merge with the Evangelical and Reformed Church to form the United Church of Christ in 1957, the First Congregational Church in Middleboro decided to instead join the National Association of Congregational Christian Churches. The first half of the twentieth-century also saw declining church membership. Membership grew after the ordination of Manfred Kohl in 1969. In 1993, the church also joined the Conservative Congregational Christian Conference. The church continues to serve the Middleboro community today.
Ministers
Samuel Fuller 1694-1695
Thomas Palmer 1702-1708
Peter Thatcher, Jr. 1709-1744
Sylvanus Conant 1745-1777
Thomas Weld 1745-1749
Elijah Packard 1753-1754
Joseph Barker 1781-1815
Emerson Paine 1816-1822
William Eaton 1824-1835
Israel W. Putnam 1835-1865
Rufus M. Sawyer 1866-1869
Ephraim N. Hidden 1869-1874
Theophilus P. Swain 1875-1878
Nathan T. Dyer 1878-1885
Howard A. Hannaford 1885-1888
Josiah W. Kingsbury 1889-1891
George W. Stearns 1891-1905
Arthur G. Cummings 1905-1954
James R. Williams 1954-1957
Warren C. Campbell 1957-1958
Albert D.C. McIlroy 1958-1968
Frank H. Oxenford 1968-1969
Manfred W. Kohl 1969-1977
Robert T. Pardon 1977-1984
Robert Olson 1984
Bruce R. Brown 1984-1991
Charles McCrillis 1991-1993
James R. Henry 1993-1997
David White 1997-1999
Peter W. Murdy 1999-present
Scope and Contents
This collection of records from the First Congregational Church in Middleboro, Massachusetts, documents the administrative history of the church and the religious life of its members. The membership records within the collection are particularly robust and include hundreds of individual's relations, marriage intentions, membership requests and dismissions, and disciplinary records. The collection includes administrative and financial records, including meeting minutes, committee reports, ecclesiastical council results, receipts, and pew records. The collection also includes manuscript sermons, the majority written by Sylvanus Conant, and some print materials related to the history of the church.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into six series, listed below. Except within the membership series, records have been arranged in chronological order, by start date. Within the membership series, records have been grouped by topics, and further divided by either alphabetical or chronological order.
Series 1: Church and parish records, 1702-1895
Series 2: Financial records, 1744-1908
Series 3: Membership records, 1741-1880
Series 4: Ministerial records, 1832-1891
Series 5: Manuscript sermons, 1737-1779
Series 6: Publications, 1759-1925
Technical Requirements
A microfilm reader is required in order to access microfilmed materials. One microfilm reader is available to the public upon request.
To access digital user's copies via online-interface, a java-enabled web browser is required. Internet Explorer 8.x and later, Firefox 5.x and later, Opera 12 and later, Safari 5.x and later, or any version of Google Chrome are recommended.
Bibliography
Book of the First Church of Christ, In Middleborough, Plymouth County, Mass. Boston: C. C. P. Moody, 1852. 17.11.1 M58.4 FirCC B 1852
"Our History." First Congregational Church in Middleboro. Accessed December 5, 2018. http://www.fccmiddleboro.org/?page_id=14.
Baptismal records.; Church discipline.; Church finance.; Church lands.; Church membership.; Church records and registers.; Church societies.; Confession.; Creeds.; Funeral sermons.; Marriage records.; New England's Hidden Histories.; Pews and pew rights.; Registers of births, etc.; Sermons, American -- Early works to 1800.; First Congregational Church (Middleboro, Mass.); Middleboro (Mass.) -- Church history.
- Church and parish records, 1702 1895; 1702-1895
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the administrative records of the church and parish in Middleboro. The series includes meeting minutes, pew plans and pew deeds, committee reports, ecclesiastical council minutes, records of the parsonage, church correspondence, and other records relating to the operation of the church.
  - Church records, 1702 1867; 1702-1867 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Church record book, 1707 1821; 1707-1821; 2009 (Reel Service Copy, Reel Print Master)
    Restrictions on Access
    Only the service copy is available for library use. The print master copies are restricted for preservation purposes.
    Location of Originals
    The location of the origional record book is currently unknown.
    Digital Copies
    These church records were digitized as part of the New England's Hidden Histories project. Digital reproductions are available to view online. In addition, transcriptions of this volume can be seen along side the digital images linked to above.
    This volume contains membership records, including admissions, dismissions, and confessions of faith, as well as records of baptisms, marriages, and a few disciplinary cases. The later pages are primarily devoted to minutes of church meetings, and includes a copy of the church covenant.
  - Deadon's declaration of duties, 1724 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Committee report on division of ministry lands, 1750 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Separated Materials
    This item was removed from the Proprietor's book, 1744-1816, for preservation purposes.
  - Church communications, 1770 1853; 1770-1853 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Robinson Society communications and complaints, 1823 1837; 1823-1837 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Robinson Society membership certificates, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committee reports, 1825 1854; 1825-1854 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pew plans and releases, circa 1828 (Folder 6)
  - Pew deeds, 1829 1881; 1829-1881 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pew releases, 1829 1834; 1829-1834 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Parsonage records, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ecclesiastical council records, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ecclesiastical council proceedings, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Prayer meeting reports, 1836 1837; 1836-1837 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Parish records, 1837 1895; 1837-1895 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Area council meetings, 1840 1851; 1840-1851 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Church "Doings" record book, 1866 1873; 1866-1873 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Church records inventory, 1866 (Box 1, Volume 3)
- Financial records, 1744 1908; 1744-1908; 14 Files; (1 volume, 13 folders)
  This series contains the financial records of the church and parish. The bulk of the series are nineteenth-century receipts that cover a wide range of payments and services rendered. The series also contains records related to the management of the church building, pew payments, charity contributions, and membership subscriptions.
  - Proprietor's book, 1744 1816; 1744-1816 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    These church records were digitized as part of the New England's Hidden Histories project. Digital reproductions are available to view online.
    This volume contains two distinct sections starting at either cover. The front of the volume contains the administrative and financial records for the precinct. The reverse of the volume contains the treasurers' records of pew fees and other payments.
  - Parish assessment and subscriptions, 1824 1866; 1824-1866 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Parish financial records, 1824 1888; 1824-1888 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Financial records, 1829 1871; 1829-1871 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Receipts, 1830 1839; 1830s (Box 1, Folder 19-21)
  - Stockholders notice, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Ecclesiastical council bills, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Receipts, 1840 1849; 1840s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Receipts, 1850 1859; 1850s (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Receipts, 1860 1869; 1860s (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Receipts, 1868 1908; 1868-1908 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Receipts, 1870 1879; 1870s (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Charity receipts, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Receipts, 1880 1900; 1880-1900 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Membership records, 1741 1880; 1741-1880; 34 Folders
  Many of the membership records found within this series have been digitized and made available online as part of the New Englands Hidden Histories project. An alphabetical index of these Relations and Personal records may be searched for easy digital access. In addition, transcriptions of the majority of these records can be seen along side the digital images.
  This series contains the church's membership records, which are largely composed of relations. Relations are written accounts of individuals' religious experience, often required in the process of applying for full membership. Many of the relations in this series are written in the congregants' own handwriting. The relations also includes related membership records, such as letters of transfer to and from other churches, requests for baptism, and confessions of sins written in order to return to the good graces of the church. In addition to relations, this series contains marriage intentions, which were recorded by the town clerk prior to marriage, membership requests, letters of dismission, disciplinary records, including testimony, and membership certificates to various religious societies.
  - Membership: A, 1743 1853; 1743-1853; 11 Items (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Alden, Elihu, 1794 1800; 1794, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 1-2)
    - Alden, Elijah, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 3)
    - Alden, Mary, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 4)
    - Alden, Noah, 1743 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 5)
    - Anthony, Alice, 1783 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 6)
    - Atwood, Joanna, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 7)
    - Atwood, John, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 8)
    - Atwood, Mary, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 9)
    - Atwood, Rhoda, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 10)
    - Atwood, Sarah Alden, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 11)
  - Membership: B, 1747 1864; 1747-1864; 45 Items (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Barker, Anna, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 1)
    - Barker, Elizabeth, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 2)
    - Barker, Eunice, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 3)
    - Baker, William, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 4)
    - Barrows, Freeman, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 5)
    - Bates, Joseph, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 6)
    - Bates, Susanna, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 7)
    - Bennet, Jacob, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 8)
    - Bennet, Mercy, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 9)
    - Bent, Experience, 1807 1825; 1807, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 10-11)
    - Billington, Deborah, 1761 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 12)
    - Billington, Eleanor, 1764 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 13)
    - Billington, Ichabod, 1762 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 14)
    - Booth, Priscilla, 1747 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 15)
    - Bosworth, Mr., 1826 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 16)
    - Bourne, Abigail, 1784 1810; 1784, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 17-18)
    - Bourne, Abner, 1782 1806; 1782, 1800, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 19-21)
    - Bourne, Joseph, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 22)
    - Bourne, Lydia, 1791 1808; 1791, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 23-24)
    - Bourne, Mary, 1783 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 25)
    - Bourne, Newcomb, 1786 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 26)
    - Bourne, Sophia, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 27)
    - Bradford, DeWitt, 1848 1864; 1848-1864 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 28-29)
    - Bradford, Lydia, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 30)
    - Brannack, Consider, 1766 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 31)
    - Briggs, Ebenezer, 1767 1785; 1767, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 32-33)
    - Briggs, George, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 34)
    - Briggs, John, 1768 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 35)
    - Briggs, Patience, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 36)
    - Brown, Elizabeth, 1782 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 37)
    - Bryant, Hannah, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 38)
    - Bryant, Jesse, 1797 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 39)
    - Bryant, Margaret, 1776 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 40)
    - Bryant, Mercy, 1797 1851; 1797, 1813, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 41-43)
    - Bump, Mercy, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 44)
    - Burgess, Temperance, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 45)
  - Membership: C, 1747 1863; 1747-1863 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Carver, Josiah and Jerusha, 1793 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 1)
    - Caswell, Benjamin, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 2)
    - Caswell, Polly, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 3)
    - Clarke, Zilpha, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 4)
    - Coade, Hannah, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 5-6)
    - Cobb, Abijah, 1765 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 7)
    - Cobb, Azubah, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 8)
    - Cobb, Binney, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 9)
    - Cobb, Ebenezer, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 10)
    - Cobb, Lydia, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 10)
    - Cobb, Jacob, 1807 1825; 1807, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 11-12)
    - Cobb, Olive, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 13)
    - Cobb, Polly, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 14)
    - Cobb, Priscilla, 1809 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 15)
    - Cole, Thomas, 1747 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 16-17)
    - Colwell, Mary Ann, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 18)
    - Cornish, Charles F., 1858 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 19)
    - Cornish, Louisa, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 20)
    - Cornish, Mary L., 1858 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 21)
    - Cornish, William, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 22)
    - Cushman, Adoniram, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 23)
    - Cushman, Ann, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 24)
    - Cushman, Deborah, 1760 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 25)
    - Cushman, Lucy Ann, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 26)
    - Cushman, Mercy, 1783 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 27)
    - Cushman, Priscilla, 1763 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 28)
    - Cushman, Susan H., 1863 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 29)
    - Cushman, Sylvia, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 30)
  - Membership: D, 1794 1859; 1794-1859 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Darling, Daniel, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 1)
    - Darling, Polly, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 2)
    - Dean, Eliab, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 3)
    - Dean, Lois, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 4)
    - Dean, Lydia, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 5)
    - Deane, Nancy, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 6)
    - Deane, Ruth, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 7)
    - Doane, Calvin, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 8)
    - Doty, Isaac, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 9)
    - Drews, Atwood, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 2)
    - Dunham, Henry, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 10)
  - Membership: E, 1765 1841; 1765-1841 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Eddy, Anna, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 1)
    - Eddy, Anne E., 1840 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 2)
    - Eddy, Betsey, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 3)
    - Eddy, Betsey M., 1831 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 4)
    - Eddy, Charlotte, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 5)
    - Eddy, Eliza, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 6)
    - Eddy, Jane Ellen, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 7)
    - Eddy, Jerusha, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 8)
    - Eddy. Joshua, 1797 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 9)
    - Eddy, Joshua, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 10)
    - Eddy, Lucy Ann, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 11)
    - Eddy, Lydia, 1797 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 12)
    - Eddy, Lydia, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 13)
    - Eddy, Lydia M., 1829 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 14)
    - Eddy, Mary Jane, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 15)
    - Eddy, Nathan, 1765 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 16)
    - Eddy, Nathaniel, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 17)
    - Eddy, Sally, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 18)
    - Eddy, Seth, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 19)
    - Eddy, Susanna, 1777 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 20)
    - Eddy, Susanna, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 21)
    - Eddy, Sylvanus, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 22)
    - Eddy, Zacharaiah, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 23)
    - Ellis, Deborah, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 24)
    - Ellis, Lucia, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 25)
    - Ellis, Lucia, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 26)
    - Ellis, Southworth, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 27)
    - Ellis, Susanna M., 1840 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 28)
  - Membership: F, 1792 1861; 1792-1861 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Finney, Margaret, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 1)
    - Finney, Martha, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 2)
    - Foley, James, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 3)
    - Freeman, Harriet, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 4)
    - Freeman, Jane, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 5)
    - Freeman, John, 1807 1846; 1807, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 6-8)
    - Freeman, Virtue, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 9)
    - Fuller, Betty, 1801 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 10)
    - Fuller, Consider, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 11)
    - Fuller, Lucy, 1807 1839; 1807, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 12-13)
    - Fuller, Sally, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 14)
    - Fuller, Sophia, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 6, Item 15)
  - Membership: G, 1813 1859; 1813-1859 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Gisby, Deborah, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 7, Item 1)
    - Gisby, Olive Elmes, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 7, Item 2-3)
    - Gisby, William, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 7, Item 4)
  - Membership: H, 1788 1840; 1788-1840 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Harlow, Betsey, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 1)
    - Harlow, Betsy, 1796 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 2)
    - Harlow, Hepzibah, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 3)
    - Harlow, Jonathan, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 4)
    - Harlow, Mercy, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 5)
    - Harlow, Sarah, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 6)
    - Harlow, Steven Jr., 1840 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 7)
    - Harrington, Lucy, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 8)
    - Haskell, Abigail, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 9)
    - Haskell, Zebulon, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 10)
    - Haskins, Jerusha, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 11)
    - Hill, Harriet, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 12)
    - Holmes, Thankful, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 13)
    - Hubbard, Serena, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 8, Item 14)
  - Membership: K, 1807 1831; 1807-1831 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Kidder, Sally, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 9, Item 1)
    - King, Mercy, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 9, Item 2)
    - King, Nathan, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 9, Item 3)
  - Membership: L, 1763 1850; 1763-1851 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Lawrence, Sarah, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 1)
    - Leach, Betsey, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 2)
    - Leach, Betty, 1763 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 3)
    - Leach, John, 1763 1792; 1763, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 4-5)
    - Leach, Phebe, 1765 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 6)
    - Leach, Susannah, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 7)
    - Leonard, Betsey, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 8)
    - Leonard, John, 1772 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 9)
    - Leonard, Lucy, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 10)
    - Leonard, Sally, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 11)
    - Ling, Jane, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 12)
    - Littlejohn, Elizabeth, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 13)
    - Lovell, Jerusha, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 14)
    - Lovell, Joseph, 1773 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 15-18)
    - Lucas, Elijah, 1789 1804; 1789, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 19-20)
    - Lucas, Sarah, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 21)
    - Lyon, Mary, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 22)
    - Lyons, Jediah, 1786 (Box 2, Folder 10, Item 23)
  - Membership: M, 1760 1853; 1760-1853 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - McFarland (Barrows), Ruth, 1782 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 1-2)
    - Meglathlin, Freeman, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 3)
    - Meglathlin, Harriet, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 4)
    - Miller, Sarah, 1782 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 5)
    - Miller, Susanna, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 6)
    - Morse, Charles, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 7)
    - Morse, Desire, 1761 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 8)
    - Morse, Desire, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 9)
    - Morse, Isaac, 1782 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 10)
    - Morse, Marston, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 11-12)
    - Morse, Mary Maria, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 13)
    - Morse, Sage, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 14)
    - Morse, Thankful, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 15)
    - Morton, Daniel, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 16)
    - Morton, Eliza, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 17)
    - Morton, Hepzibah, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 18)
    - Morton, Ichabod, 1760 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 19)
    - Morton, Lendall, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 20)
    - Muxham, Edmund, 1773 (Box 2, Folder 11, Item 21)
  - Membership: N-O, 1771 1859; 1771-1859 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Nichols, Marie Lucia, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 12, Item 1)
    - Norcull, Mary, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 12, Item 2)
    - Norcutt, Mary, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 12, Item 3)